Silvère Gangloff

Researcher

29 years old, Married



Fontainebleau, France



+33 749193317



https://sfgangloff.github.io/

@

silvere.gangloff@gmx.com

About me

I am an autonomous researcher and thinker, curious about everything of my direct and distant environment, who constantly seeks to push the limits of his understanding and knowledge. I am also a passionate teacher, who tries to understand his students to provide them lessons adapted to them.

Skills

Team communication (Slack, Notion)

Debugging (VScode)

Modeling

Data visualisation

Statistics

Machine and Deep learning (NLP)

Frameworks (Jupyter, Anaconda).

Databases (SQLite)

Javascript

Unix

Python, Keras

English (writing and speaking)

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

Education

2015-2018 Aix-Marseille University

PhD in mathematics and computer science - Title: Algorithmic complexity of growth-type invariants for multidimensional subshifts of finite time under dynamical constraints. (manuscript). Publication of several articles presenting important results in my field (in international peer-review journals).

2011-2015 ENS Paris (also called ENS Ulm, Normale'sup)

Major in Mathematics, Minors in Biology, History, Philosophy, Cognitive sciences

2013-2014 Pierre et Marie Curie University (UPMC)

Master in mathematics (Dynamical systems specialty).

2014-2015 University of Toulouse, Paul Sabatier

Research internship (game theory and dynamical systems), agrégation de mathématiques (39th).

Experience

Oct.2020-now IziMade-AI, Station F (Paris)

(CDI) Development and research (Machine learning, NLP)

2019-Oct.2020University of Wisconsin-Madison (psychiatry department)

(CDD) Multidisciplinary research

- Developed innovative tools for (theoretical) machine learning (based on brain architecture).
- Data visualization of brain activity and pattern analysis.
- Self-formation: followed machine learning and data science class of Stephane Mallat (Collège de France), and reading F.Chollet's book Deep Learning with Python.

2018-2019 ENS Lyon (department of computer science)

(CDD) Research and teaching

- Wrote a complete and rigorous proof for the value of entropy of a major model in statistical physics (publication).
- Organised by myself a work group (gathering researchers in mathematics, computer science and physics).
- Teached programming (Python) and Turing machines at the university.
- Developped tools to manage researchers and allow communication between researchers from different fields.
- Used gitlab to communicate work documents with other researchers and github and javascript to code my professional webpage.

Soft Skills

I systematically take work experience as an occasion to learn in many directions, in a way that is efficient enough to make substantial (and important) contributions. In doing so, I take advantage of my ability to adapt to and use other mindsets and respond appropriately to positive or negative feedback. I am able to deal with complex structures and large amounts of information in order to provide solutions to difficult problems and explain complex notions to others. I am attentive to detail and rigour and have a creative mind with constant original ideas. When I communicate, I am able to combine precision and conciseness and to adapt to the target audience. As well, I know how to adapt my writing style to various formats (from few lines abstracts to book-length articles). During my doctoral thesis, I developed the ability to multi-task in an independent way, work effectively under pressure and meet deadlines (for publications and presentations in conferences). The search for jobs in research was the occasion to conceive and write some projects.